<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>SketchnoteSara - Asynchronous Sketchnotes</title><link href="https://www.sketchnotesara.ch/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.sketchnotesara.ch/feeds/asynchronous-sketchnotes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.sketchnotesara.ch/</id><updated>2023-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Social Media Campaign about Participatory Autism Research for Academische Werkplaats Autisme</title><link href="https://www.sketchnotesara.ch/social-media-campaign-about-participatory-autism-research-for-academische-werkplaats-autisme.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara</name></author><id>tag:www.sketchnotesara.ch,2023-04-02:/social-media-campaign-about-participatory-autism-research-for-academische-werkplaats-autisme.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 'Academische Werkplaats Autisme' performs participatory and practice-based research. Researchers, autistic individuals and their family members, professionals and policy makers collaborate in prioritizing, designing and carrying out research projects that focus on support to improve participation of autistic children, adolescents and adults in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collaborated with them to make …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 'Academische Werkplaats Autisme' performs participatory and practice-based research. Researchers, autistic individuals and their family members, professionals and policy makers collaborate in prioritizing, designing and carrying out research projects that focus on support to improve participation of autistic children, adolescents and adults in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I collaborated with them to make some drawings for a social media campaign about participatory research in English and Dutch. 
For this collaboration I created 4 drawings and a title slide, based on a presentation that had been recorded on the topic. 
After incorporating feedback and translating the texts on the images the campaign was launched on World Autism Day 2023. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Asynchronous Sketchnotes"></category></entry><entry><title>Sketchnote of Research Article on independent Living with Autism</title><link href="https://www.sketchnotesara.ch/sketchnote-of-research-article-on-independent-living-with-autism.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sara</name></author><id>tag:www.sketchnotesara.ch,2023-01-18:/sketchnote-of-research-article-on-independent-living-with-autism.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sketchnote in 10 square formatted social media drawings of an article by Phuong Nguyen, Viviana d’Auria and Ann Heylighen from 2020: Understanding Independent Living with Autism: The Role of the Housing Environment in the Experiences of Two Autistic Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cpcl.unibo.it/article/view/10781"&gt;The full article can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It asks what …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sketchnote in 10 square formatted social media drawings of an article by Phuong Nguyen, Viviana d’Auria and Ann Heylighen from 2020: Understanding Independent Living with Autism: The Role of the Housing Environment in the Experiences of Two Autistic Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cpcl.unibo.it/article/view/10781"&gt;The full article can be found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It asks what independent living means to autistic adults and talks to 2 of them living in housing projects with so called friendly neighbours. Themes discussed are proximity, self-determination and social contact. Throughout the discussion of the themes different social and physical factors of the housing environment come up: especially the support network, smalltalk, and building layout turn out to be key factors. They conclude with repeating how all those factors interrelate, and how the facilitation of independent living should be informed by the lived experience of autistic people themselves. (I added a nothing about us, without us banner.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Asynchronous Sketchnotes"></category></entry></feed>